lexblog.com 2016-04-05

# Privacy Policy | LexBlog

**INTRODUCTION**  
LexBlog (“we”, “us”, or “our”) respects your privacy and is committed to maintaining the privacy and confidentiality of any personal data we collect either through LexBlog.com (“Site”) or through our managed hosting services (“Services”). The purpose of this Privacy Policy is to inform you of our personal data collection, use and processing practices. If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, please feel free to contact us at the information provided below.

**SAFE HARBOR**  
When We are the Data Controller. We comply with the U.S.-EU Safe Harbor Framework and the U.S.-Swiss Safe Harbor Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal data from European Union member countries and Switzerland. We have certified that we adhere to the Safe Harbor Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data integrity, access, and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbor program, and to view our certification, please visit <http://www.export.gov/safeharbor/>.

When We are the Data Processor. Our obligations with respect to personal data for which we are the data processor, such as personal data that our customers store or transfer using the Services, are defined in its agreements with our customers and are not included in this Privacy Policy. In those circumstances we receive personal data from the EU as an agent of the customer merely for processing and are not required to apply Safe Harbor principles to that information. The customer remains responsible for the personal data that it collects and processes and for the compliance with applicable data protection laws. If you have any questions about how our customers use your personal data, please contact them directly.

**COOKIES & OTHER TECHNOLOGIES ON THE SITE**  
Like most website operators, we collect non-personally-identifying information of the sort that web browsers and servers typically make available, such as the browser type, language preference, referring site, and the date and time of each visitor request. We may release non-personally-identifying information in the aggregate, e.g., by publishing a report on trends in the usage of its website. We use analytical software to help us understand this information. This software sends information to its licensor. Other sites and companies may also use this software. As a result, the licensor may collect information, that when aggregated by them, allows them to identify you individually. We have no responsibility for this collection and use.

We also collect information like Internet Protocol (IP) addresses from Site visitors. LexBlog only discloses logged in user and commenter IP addresses under the same circumstances that it uses and discloses personally-identifying information as described below, except that blog commenter IP addresses are visible and disclosed to the administrators of the blog where the comment was left. Combined with other information, it is possible to use this information in the aggregate to identify you individually. To delete session cookies, simply close your web browser or turn off the computer’s power. The session cookies will be deleted automatically. Simply closing your web browser or turning off your computer will not delete persistent cookies. In order to delete persistent cookies, you will need to manually delete them through your browser’s settings options. You can disable both session and persistent cookies by adjusting the settings on your web browser. For instructions on disabling cookies, click here.

**PERSONAL DATA YOU PROVIDE TO US**  
In order to use our Services, and other features of our website, we will ask you for personal data (e.g. contact information, name, etc.). The amount and type of information that we gather depends on the nature of the interaction. Those who purchase Services from us are asked to provide information, including, as necessary, the personal and financial information required to process transactions. In each case, LexBlog collects such information only insofar as is necessary or appropriate to fulfill the purpose of the visitor’s interaction with LexBlog. LexBlog does not disclose personal data other than as described below. You can always refuse to supply personal data, however, doing so will prevent you from receiving Services and may prevent you from engaging in other activities. In no event will we ever gather sensitive personal data (e.g. health information, religious preferences, etc.) from you and we expressly request that you not provide any to us in any free-text fields that are present on the Site.

**PROTECTION OF PERSONAL DATA**  
We disclose personal data only to our employees and third parties that need to know that information in order to process it on our behalf or to help provide the Services and have agreed not to disclose it to others. Some of those employees or third parties may be located outside of your home country (e.g. in the United States); by using the Site or signing up for the Services, you consent to the transfer of such information to them. We will not rent or sell personal data to anyone other than in conjunction with the sale of our business. Other than described in this Privacy Policy, we disclose personal data only when required to do so by law, or when we believe in good faith that disclosure is reasonably necessary to protect our property or rights or third parties or the public at large. If you are our customer, we will occasionally send you emails to tell you about new features, solicit your feedback, or just keep you up to date with what is going on at LexBlog. If you send us a request (for example, via a support email or via one of our feedback mechanisms), we reserve the right to publish it in order to help us clarify or respond to your request or to help us support other users. We own all such feedback. We may also disclose or transmit personal data to third parties in these specific situations:

In response to a subpoena, court order, or other valid legal process.  
To prevent, investigate, or stop illegal or malicious activities including violations of our acceptable use policy, threats to our facilities, and threats to the physical safety of any person.  
To our affiliated companies or to any entity that acquires majority control of us or one of our business units through merger, acquisition, consolidation, or otherwise.

**E-MAIL OPT-OUT**  
You may opt-out of receiving most e-mails from us by following the “unsubscribe” instructions provided in the e-mails. Alternatively, you may contact us at the information provided below.

**COOKIES**  
A cookie is a string of information that a website stores on a visitor’s computer, and that the visitor’s browser provides to the website each time the visitor returns. LexBlog uses cookies to help LexBlog identify and track visitors, their usage of LexBlog website, and their website access preferences. LexBlog visitors who do not wish to have cookies placed on their computers should set their browsers to refuse cookies before using LexBlog’s websites, with the drawback that certain features of LexBlog’s websites may not function properly without the aid of cookies.

**COMMENTS**  
Your name, screen name (if provided), website and comments will be made public on our blog.

**CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY**  
Although most changes are likely to be minor, we may change this Privacy Policy from time to time, and in our sole discretion. We encourage you to frequently check this page for any changes to our Privacy Policy. If we make a change to this Privacy Policy, we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account, if applicable) or by means of a notice on this website prior to the change becoming effective. All such changes are effective at the time set out in our notice. If you disagree with such a change, you may discontinue use of the Services or Site without penalty or early termination charge.

**APPROPRIATE PROCEDURES**  
We have put in place reasonable measures and appropriate procedures for implementing these policies and for safeguarding the information we collect from you. However, we cannot guarantee that personal data we collect will never be disclosed in a manner inconsistent with this Privacy Policy.

**CHANGING INFORMATION**  
If you would like to change information we maintain about you, you may log into your account and change it. If it is information you are unable to access, you may contact us at legal[at]lexblog.com. Information covered by this Privacy Policy may be deleted upon a customer’s request. We may keep information covered by this Privacy Policy for a period of twelve months from the date of a customer’s termination of their relationship with us, or as required by law. Also, you may request that we update or correct your personal data by contacting us at legal[at]lexblog.com.

**DMCA WEBSITE NOTICE**  
If you believe a LexBlog customer on a site hosted by LexBlog is infringing your copyright, please send a written notice to:

Legal  
LexBlog, Inc.  
710 Second Ave  
Suite 660  
Seattle, WA 98104  
800-913-0988  
abuse[at]lexblog.com

Section 512(c) of the DMCA requires that a notice include all of the following in order to be valid:

  * A physical or electronic signature of a person authorized to act on behalf of the owner of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed
  * Identification of the copyrighted work claimed to have been infringed, or if multiple copyrighted works at a single site are covered by a single notification, a representative list of such works at that site
  * Identification of the material that is claimed to be infringing or to be the subject of infringing activity and that is to be removed or access to which is to be disabled, and information reasonably sufficient to permit LexBlog to locate the material
  * Information reasonably sufficient to permit LexBlog to contact you, such as an address, telephone number, and, if available, an e-mail address
  * A statement that you have a good faith belief that use of the material in the manner complained of is not authorized by the copyright owner, its agent, or the law
  * A statement that the information in the notification is accurate, and under penalty of perjury, that you are copyright owner or authorized to act on behalf of the owner of an exclusive right that is allegedly infringed
  * You acknowledge that if you fail to comply with all of the foregoing requirements your DMCA notice may not be valid and LexBlog may take no action
